A Finding Aid to the Jud Fine and Barbara McCarren Papers, circa 1968-2009, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Project Files, circa 1988-2009; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 14.4 Linear feet Boxes 2-20; Oversize 21; 0.345 Gigabytes ER0001-ER0005
  - Santa Clara Valley Transportation Authority (SCVTA), Archival Resource Key
    - Art Plan, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Design Vision Proposal, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Maps, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Drawings, Renderings (Campbell), circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Plans and Drawings, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 20)
    - Plans and Drawings, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 21)
    - Notes, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Invoices, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Expenses, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Press Clippings, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Project Documents, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Research Material, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Santa Monica Boulevard Streetscape, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, Department of Public Works, Cultural Affairs, 1997-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, Marje Kaspar, circa 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Contract, Metropolitan Transportation Authority, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Contract, Cultural Affairs Department, circa 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Contract, circa 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Architects, circa 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Budget, circa 2002-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Streetscape Plans, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Meeting Notes, circa 1997-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Public Art Study Report, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Public Art Study Report Drafts, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Urban Design Strategy Report, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Art Plan, Concept, circa 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Horizon Alignment Study, circa 2002; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records; see ER0003. (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Horizon Alignment Study, Digital Documents (Autocad), 2001, 2002; Archival Resource Key; 0.028 Gigabytes Four computer files (Folder ER0003)
    - Transit Parkway Plans, circa 2004-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Streetscape Plans, circa 2004-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Drawings, circa 1998, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Aluminum Icons, circa 2004-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Storyland Icon, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Brackets, circa 2002-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
    - Light Poles, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Retaining Wall, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Furniture Options (Department of Public Works Street Services), circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Curb Ramps (Bureau of Engineering), circa 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Notes, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Insurance, circa 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Invoices, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Quotations, circa 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Maintenance Questionnaire, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Printed Material, Clippings, circa 1997-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Installation Documents, circa 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Material Resources, circa 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Arizona, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - California, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Illinois, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Kansas, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Missouri, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - New Mexico, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Oklahoma, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Texas, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1998-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Research Material, circa 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Santa Monica Centaline Gateway Proposal, circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Santa Monica Filter (Dry Weather Runoff Reclamation), Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, Promotional Material, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Dry Weather Runoff Concept Plan, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Dry Weather Runoff Project Plan, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Dry Weather Runoff, Project Approach, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Drawings, Plans, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Proposal Presentation (July 31, 1996), circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Dry Weather Runoff Reclamation Facility Report, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Montgomery Watson, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Notes, circa 1992-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 37-38)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 39-40)
  - Scan, Sony, Culver City Studios, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Contract Correspondence, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Budget, circa 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Studio Construction, circa 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Artwork Plan, circa 1993-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Designs, circa 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Gregory Abbott (Krohn Design), 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Nipkow Disk, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Niall Kelly, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Meeting Handouts, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - WIL Text Draft, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Studio Plaque Text, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Notes, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Bibliography, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Research Material, Television History, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Research Material, Television Technology, circa 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Southern California Rapid Transit, Art in Transit Program, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Spine, Los Angeles Central Library, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, circa 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Komar and Melamid, circa 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Maguire Tomas Partners, circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Sanders Studio, circa 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Tower Lobby, Maguire Thomas Partners Consultants, circa 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Contract, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Contract, West Lawn, circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Art Plan, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Art Plan, Concept Draft, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Publication Proposal, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Book Selections Not Used, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Book Early Drafts, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - MS Edits, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Permissions, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - KRC Rock, circa 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Expenses, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Drawings, Diagrams, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Thoughts on the Steps "Evolution of Civil Liberties", circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Fine Artist Statement, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Manuscript Inserts, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Scallops, circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Grotto Fountain, circa 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - West Lawn, Construction Notes, circa 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 24-25)
    - Notes, Drafts, circa 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Photographic Material, Xerox Masters, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Photographic Material (Pools, Wells, Spouts), circa 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Research Material, Typeface, circa 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Research Material (Pools, Wells, Spouts), circa 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 31-32)
    - Research Material, circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - The Strand, Huntington Beach, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence (Contruction), circa 2003-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Contract, circa 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Contract, Change Orders, 2004-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Budget, Financial, circa 2004-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - General Design Concept, circa 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Project Description, circa 2007-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Art Plan, 2004; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records; see ER0004. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Art Plans, Digital Documents, 2004, 2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.186 Gigabytes Four computer files (Folder ER0004)
    - Art Plan, Draft and Budget, circa 2004-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Art Plans (Digital, Maya), 2004, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Plans Not Used, circa 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Paramount, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Subcontractors, circa 2004-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Plan Drawings, Original, circa 2004-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Drawings, circa 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Drawings, Huntington, circa 2005-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Engineering Drawings, circa 2004-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Plans and Drawings, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - CAD Drawings, circa 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Waterline Pier Plans, circa 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Design Review Board, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Meetings, circa 2004-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - CIM Group Presentation (May 6 2004), circa 2004, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Huntington Beach Staff Presentation (Jul. 28 2004), circa 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Revised 5th Street Layout, circa 2005-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Insurance, 2004-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Invoices, 2004-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Paving, circa 2004; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records; see ER0004. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Barnacle Bros., 2008; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records; see ER0005. (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Barnacle Bros., Digital Photographs and Videos, 2008; Archival Resource Key; 0.063 Gigabytes 13 computer files (Folder ER0005)
    - Bridge Pilings, circa 2007-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Bridge Piers and Pilings, circa 2004-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Lighting, circa 2006-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - LED Lighting, circa 2006-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Sun Wall and Wave Wall, circa 2006-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Wave Sculpture and Fountain Area, circa 2006-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Materials, Construction, circa 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Materials, Pavers, circa 2004-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Press Clippings, circa 2004-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Notes, circa 2004, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 31-32)
    - Photographic Material, circa 2006-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Research Material, circa 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Venice, Art for Crossroads, Archival Resource Key
    - Contracts, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Department of Cultural Affairs, circa 1993-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - CAD Drawings, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Fabrication, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Invoices, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Notes, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Venice, Oceanfront Walk Refurbishment, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, circa 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Contract, DJM Construction, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Contract, circa 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Budget, circa 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Project Description, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Oceanfront Walk Refurbishment Plan (Nov. 1995), circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Plans and Updates, circa 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Art Plan, Final (Dec. 1999), Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Bill Attaway Sculpture, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Fabrication (Flagpoles, Etc.), circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Poetry Walls, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Blowhole, Water Feature, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Notes, circa 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
    - Research Material, circa 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Ventura River Trail, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, circa 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - General, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Contract, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Contract, 1997, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Contract, Scope of Work, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Budget, circa 1996-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Preliminary Report (May 13, 1996), Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Drawings, Sketches, Drafts, circa 1996-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Scope of Services, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Allen Quigley Design Development, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Tom Boyd, Boyle Engineering Corporation, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Progress Meetings, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Installation, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Community Artists, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Other Artists, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Field Copy, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Interpretive Material, circa 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Press Clippings, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Notes, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Research Material, Numerology, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Research Material, Mark 33, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Research Material, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Why Se Pac Art, Costa Mesa, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, circa 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Plans, Notes, circa 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Public Art Applications and Proposals, circa 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 37-39)
  - Public Art Applications and Proposals, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Sketches, Miscellaneous Projects, circa 1984-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
- Printed Material, circa 1974-1992; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 16
  Printed material includes various promotional materials for McCarren/Fine and solo projects for Barbara McCarren and Jud Fine, as well as a graphic design magazine publication, and a monographic catalog for a Jud Fine exhibition from 1974.
  - Or an Introduction, by Jud Fine; Dayton's Gallery 12, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Font and Function Magazine (Winter 1992), Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Announcements and Reviews, circa 1988-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Photographic Material, circa 1970s-2000; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.1 Linear feet Box 16
  Photographic material includes miscellaneous snapshots and snapshot albums, some of Fine and McCarren, in the studio and with artist friends, as well as an untitled album with study images of a strelitzia plant.
  - A Conversation Between Jud Fine, Francis Colpitt, and Michael H. Smith, Photographs by Robert Flick, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1970s-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Artwork, circa 1980s; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1 Folder Box 16
  Artwork includes a single, unsigned painted work on canvas that has been cut awat from the frame or support.
  - Untitled Painting, Acrylic and Pen on Canvas, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 9)